Guide to the Allan Gurganus Papers, 1961-2019 RL.11748
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1972-2018; undated
  - Uncollected Works, 1973-2014; undated
    - Notes and drafts, M-T, 1973-1975; 1992-1999; 2000-2012; undated; 44 folders (Box 18)
      Includes drafts and copies: My Magic Lantern Talk notebook; My Mother and the Hair-do's of the Staff; Notes for a Talk to People of Faith Against the Death Penalty; Now the Feds are Paying Us Not to Grow One Thing, What Shall We Export From Eastern North Carolina?; O, The Blackberries of 51!; Ode to Boy; Old Houses and Young Men; On Being Alone; One Family Repeatedly; On Whether to Purge the Dead from One's Address Book; The Passable Kingdom; The Picker's Tale; Pocket Watch Goes North; Reynolds Price memorial draft; Reynolds Price review; The Promissory Glance of David Verano; P.T. Barnum and my Great-Great Granddad's Slaves; The Punishment for Suicides; The Rebellion Continues, at Least in the Southern Short Story; Rental Garden; Rough Sketch in Evergreen: Toward the Resurrection of Charles Dudley Warner; Rumor Has It; Sailor: A Macho Fish Story for the Guy of Today; The Scavenger Hunt for 1850; Scott Fitzgerald at 100: The Most Gifted Jazz Baby, with correspondence; See Me in the Movies: The Author Goes on Location with His Oldest Living Confederate Widow; The Sense of Life: Paintings by Melissa Meyer; Seven Details: The Major Critic of the Show Felt to be Overexplicit; Shell Castle; Shep, A Dog of Our Time; Soldiers and Sailors Like to Take Showers; So Long 20th Century Heroism; Something About My Father; Soot, Spit, and the Silence: Imagining Now and Why James Castle Drew; A Stolen Bible is a Noticed Bible; Strangers on a Train; Sufficient Candy: A Racial Memory; The Tailor and the Leg; The Taste of Game; A Tissue of Lies; Tomb of the Unknown Citizen; and A Torrent of Kindness.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1975 (Box 24)
        Includes a review of Surface of the Earth by Reynolds Price.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1984 Oct 14 (Box 23)
        Includes A Public Denial.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, oversized, 1991 (Box 24)
        Includes Relax, It's Almost Over.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1991 Dec 1 (Box 25)
        Includes A Sendak Christmas.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1992; 2002; 3 items (Box 22)
        Includes My Summer in a Garden with an introduction by Allan Gurganus; and Ode to Boy, published in The Yale Review.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, oversized, 1995 Aug 22 (Box 24)
        Includes The State of Tobacco.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1997 Jun 26 (Box 23)
        Includes SEP Fiction galley.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, oversized, 1999 Oct 2 (Box 24)
        Includes A Torrent of Kindness.
    - Notes and drafts, T-Y, 1989-1999; undated; 21 folders (Box 19)
      Includes drafts and copies: Toward a More Precise Identification of Newer Angels; Toward a New Romanticism?; To War Again; War Story; We, the Improbable Heirs Yaddo in the 1980's; We, of Weedland; We Wish For a Good Young Country Doctor; Welty, Eudora; When Everything Was Funny; Where Babies Come From; White Like Us; Whitman-Eakins talk; Whitman: A Candidate for the Future Speech; Why Charleston Won't Commit to Me; The World is a Painted Wall; Writers Dreaming; Xmas; Yaddo and American Film; Yaddo Essay 100th Anniversary; and You, As a House.
      - Notes and drafts, Sister Eudora, oversized, 1999 (Box 24)
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1989 (Box 23)
        Includes The Most Truthful Liar?.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 1991 (Box 67)
        Includes What's Wrong With This Picture, from A Sendak Christmas, published in The New York Times Book Review.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, oversized, 1993 (Box 24)
        Includes Why We March.
      - Proofs and galleys, published works, 2014 (Box 19)
        Includes We are Fossils from the Future, published by the Master of Fine Arts in Experimental and Documentary Arts program in association with the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University.
    - Untitled Works, 2003; undated
      Includes untitled and undated drafts; fragments; illustrations; notes; poems; and scripts.
      - Untitled works, 2003; undated; 19 folders (Box 19)
      - Untitled works, undated; 51 folders (Box 20)
  - Addresses and Speeches, 1991-2018; undated
    This subseries includes addresses and speeches written and given by Gurganus and is arranged chronologically where dates are available.
    - Poets and Writers Twentieth Anniversary gala, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Yaddo and American film, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Iowa Writers' Workshop, 2010 Apr 30 (Box 20)
      Includes If Fiction is a Form of History, How is History Itself Not Fictional?: A Talk.
    - St. David's School commencement (Box 20)
    - Graduation address, Bennington MFAs, 2018 Jan (Box 20)
    - Acceptance speech for Lammie, fiction, undated (Box 20)
    - Bessie Schonberg introduction, undated (Box 20)
    - Lecture on the south in memory, undated (Box 20)
    - Whitman: A candidate for the future, undated (Box 20)
- Correspondence, 1961-2019; undated
  The Correspondence Series is divided into the Chronological Correspondence subseries and the Correspondence, Alphabetical by Name subseries. The Chronological Correspondence subseries consists of letters to and from Gurganus. Correspondents include family, friends, artists, and admirers of his work. These letters concern both personal and literary matters. Frequently the correspondents commented on each other's recent publications and work, or on projects in progress.
  - Correspondence, Chronological, 1961-2019
    This subseries includes correspondence between Gurganus and his family, friends, associates, students, and business contacts, and is arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1993; 13 folders (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1994-2019; 10 folders (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, oversize, 2017 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence, Alphabetical by Name, 1966-2018; undated
    This subseries includes correspondence between Gurganus and other artists, his family, and friends, and is arranged by last name of the correspondent, or company name. Where known, the occupation of the correspondent is included. Many Correspondence folders contain a limited number of items.
    - Abelson, Donald S., 1991 (Box 28)
    - Adams, Pat (painter), 1989; undated (Box 28)
    - Ajay, Steve (writer), 1982 (Box 28)
    - Allen, Kenny, 1995 (Box 28)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1990-2007 (Box 28)
    - Anderson, Julian, 1984-1989 (Box 28)
    - Appffel, Edmund, 1981-1985 (Box 28)
    - Appel, Richard, 1993-1994 (Box 28)
      Includes a television script from The Simpsons.
    - Arimondi, Victor (photographer), 1996 (Box 28)
    - The Asheville School, 1989 (Box 28)
    - Athas, Daphne (writer), 1990 (Box 28)
    - Averill, Brett (newspaper editor), 1982-1990 (Box 28)
      Includes photographs.
    - Baenen, Michael, 1982; undated (Box 28)
    - Ballantine, Del Rey, Fawcett, Ivy, 1991-1992 (Box 28)
    - Banks, Russell (writer), 1991 (Box 28)
    - Barkway, Stephen (writer), 1993-2018 (Box 28)
    - Beattie, Ann (writer), 2012 (Box 28)
    - Beavon, Constance (opera singer), 1983-1995 (Box 28)
    - Becket Logan Photography, 1989 (Box 28)
    - Belzer, Judith (painter), 1996 (Box 28)
      Judith Belzer is married to Michael Pollan.
    - Berghausen, Sara Seten (curator), 2016 (Box 28)
    - Bernard, Andre, 1989 (Box 28)
    - Betts, Doris (writer), undated (Box 28)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth (poet), 1975 (Box 28)
    - Black, Robin (writer), 1989 (Box 28)
    - Blangsted, Else (music editor), 1991 (Box 28)
    - Bonner, Jay (Asheville School), 1981-2018 (Box 28)
    - Bourjaily, Tina, 1976-1993 (Box 28)
    - Boyle, T.C. (writer), 1993 (Box 28)
    - Bram, Chris (writer), 1989-1998 (Box 28)
    - Bromwell, Henry (writer), 1976 (Box 28)
    - Brown, Larry (writer), 1990 (Box 28)
    - Buchanan, Jeff, 1982-1988; undated (Box 28)
    - Buford, Bill (writer), 1989 (Box 28)
    - Burns, Ken (filmmaker), 1990 (Box 28)
    - Burstyn, Ellen (actor), 2011 (Box 28)
    - Caldwell, Joe (writer), 1989-2013; undated (Box 28)
    - Calisher, Hortense (writer), 1990-1991 (Box 28)
    - Candida Donadio and Associates, 1976-1990; undated (Box 28)
    - Carbonneau, Suzzanne (art historian), 2010 (Box 28)
    - Carpenter, Carleton (actor), 2016 (Box 28)
    - Carver, Raymond (writer), 1981 (Box 28)
    - Chibka, Robert (writer), 1975-1995 (Box 28)
    - Clinton, Bill (politician), 1995 (Box 29)
    - Cole, Steven (opera singer), 1983 (Box 29)
    - Conroy, Frank (writer), 1994 (Box 29)
    - Cooper, Jane (poet), 1988-1990 (Box 29)
    - Crawford, Dean (writer), undated (Box 29)
    - Cuthrell, Hiram Johnson, 1988; undated (Box 29)
    - D'Agata, John (writer), 2015; undated (Box 29)
    - Delillo, Don (writer), 1989 (Box 29)
    - Del Tredici, David (composer), 1981-1983; undated (Box 29)
    - Doctorow, E. L. (writer), 1975 (Box 29)
    - Doyle, Ursula (writer), undated (Box 29)
    - Drechsel, Shirley, undated (Box 29)
    - Drisch, Russell (artist), 1989 (Box 29)
    - Eatman, Ed, 1990-1995 (Box 29)
    - Eatman, George (attorney), 1978-2014; undated; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Eatman, George, and John Craft, 1978-1986 (Box 29)
    - Edgerton, Catherine (artist), undated (Box 29)
    - Eiben, Therese (writer), 1989-1993 (Box 29)
    - Eil, David (economist, attorney), 1989 (Box 29)
    - Eliason, Joyce (television writer and producer), 1990-1991 (Box 29)
    - Elkin, Stanley (writer), 1976 (Box 29)
    - Ettlinger, Marion (photographer), 1990 (Box 29)
    - Faber and Faber, 1990-1998 (Box 30)
    - Faber and Faber, 1991 (Box 42)
    - Faust, Irvin (author, educator), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Field, Edward (poet), undated (Box 30)
    - Fitzgerald, Thom (film and theater director), 1998; undated (Box 30)
    - Fox, Paula (writer), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Frank, Daniel, 1995-1996 (Box 30)
    - Fraser, Luke (nephew), 1990-1994 (Box 30)
    - Freiert, Jeff (writer), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Galvin, Jim (poet), 2017 (Box 30)
    - Garrett, George (poet), 1997; undated (Box 30)
    - Gingher, Marianne (writer), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Godwin, Gail (writer), 1982 (Box 30)
    - Gordon, John (writer), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Gornick, Vivian (writer), 1982 (Box 30)
    - Grace, Nancy (legal commentator), 1982-1984 (Box 30)
    - Graham, Nan (writer), undated (Box 30)
    - Graham, Philip (writer), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Grealey, Mary Beth (film producer), undated (Box 30)
    - Grumbach, Doris (writer), 1988-1996 (Box 30)
    - Gurganus, Allan, 1988-2006; undated; 3 folders (Box 30)
      Includes correspondence from Allan Gurganus to named and unnamed correspondents. Much of this correspondence was written by Gurganus and faxed to recipients. Due to Gurganus's familiarity with his correspondents, many documents do not contain names, or are addressed affectionately to Dear One, Dearest, or Dear Heart.
    - Haffenden, John (professor), 1975 (Box 30)
    - Hall, John, 1995 (Box 30)
    - Hammer, Langdon (professor), 1983 (Box 30)
    - Handy, Amy (writer), 1966-2006 (Box 30)
    - Harnack, Curt (writer), 1990-1994 (Box 30)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1988-1995 (Box 30)
      Includes correspondence from Harper's executive editor, and author, Michael Pollan.
    - Harper, Michael S. (poet), 1989 (Box 30)
    - Harper, Wally (theater director, arranger and composer), 1992 (Box 30)
    - Hazard, Shirley (writer), 1995 (Box 30)
    - Hedbring, John T., 1989 (Box 30)
    - Hill, Jonathan, 1991 (Box 30)
      Includes the Helms for Senate newsletter that mentions Gurganus' anti-Helms efforts.
    - Hirsch, Tom, 1989 (Box 30)
    - Holding, Jane (actor), 1998-2016 (Box 30)
    - Holding, Jane, 1990 (Box 42)
    - Huffman, John (professor), 2002 (Box 30)
    - Humphreys, Josephine (writer), 1989-1999 (Box 30)
    - Hunnewell, Susannah (editor, publisher), 1996 (Box 30)
    - International Creative Management (ICM), 1990-1998; undated (Box 30)
      Binky Urban at ICM optioned the motion picture rights for He's One Too.
    - Iowa University, 1975-1989 (Box 30)
    - Irving, John (writer), 2013 (Box 30)
    - Jarman, Mark (poet), undated (Box 30)
    - Johnson, Diane (writer), 1997 (Box 30)
    - Kaiser, Dan, 1996 (Box 31)
    - Kayafas, Peter (photographer), 1999 (Box 31)
    - Kenan, Randall (writer), 1992-1998 (Box 31)
    - Kirchwey, Karl (poet), 1986-2004 (Box 31)
    - Knopf, 1989-2006 (Box 31)
    - Kringle, Dolly, 1976 (Box 31)
      Dolly Kringle was Wallace Stegner's secretary.
    - Kuralt, Charles (journalist), 1991-1996 (Box 31)
    - Lachterman-Singer, Brett (writer), undated (Box 31)
    - Lauterback, Ann (poet), 1980 (Box 31)
    - Lewis, Heather (writer), 1990-1995; undated (Box 31)
    - L'Heureux, John (writer), 1990-1991 (Box 31)
    - Liebermann, Lowell (composer), 1996 (Box 31)
    - Link, Thomas, 1981; undated (Box 31)
    - Literary Network, 1993 (Box 31)
      Includes update to NEA controversy.
    - Logan, Liz (writer, editor), 1990 (Box 31)
    - Mackle, Joanna, undated (Box 31)
    - MacNeil, Robert "Robin" (television news anchor), 1991 (Box 31)
    - Margolies, Malka (writer), 1992 (Box 31)
    - Margolis, Margo (painter), undated (Box 31)
    - Marlette, Doug (editorial cartoonist), 2001 (Box 31)
    - Mattes, Jed (literary agent), 1989 (Box 31)
    - Maxwell, William (writer), 1990-1991 (Box 31)
      William Maxwell was Allan Gurganus' first editor.
    - McCarthy, Rebecca (writer), 1989-1997 (Box 31)
    - McClatchy, Sandy (poet), 1996-1998 (Box 31)
    - McCorkle, Susannah (singer), 1982 (Box 31)
    - McCracken, E. (writer), 1995; undated (Box 31)
    - McElwee, Ross (filmmaker), 1998 (Box 31)
    - McGarrell, Ann and Jim (poet, and printmaker), 1996 (Box 31)
    - McGuirk, Leslie (illustrator), 1989-1992 (Box 31)
    - Meadow, Lynne (theater producer), 1989-1991; undated (Box 31)
    - Meeland, Ron, 1989 (Box 31)
    - Merkin, Daphne (critic), 1982-1988; undated (Box 31)
    - Merriam, Clark Lee (Cousteau Society), 1989 (Box 31)
    - Meschery, Joanne (writer), 1981-1989; undated (Box 31)
    - Messer, Sarah (poet), 2002; undated (Box 31)
    - Meyer, Melissa, 1982 (Box 31)
    - Meyer Melina, 1998 Feb 3 (Box 42)
    - Miner, Todd, 1989 (Box 31)
    - Minkin, Bertram (writer), 1975 (Box 31)
    - Minter, Drew (opera singer), 1993 (Box 31)
    - Moody, Rick (writer), undated (Box 31)
    - Moose, Ruth (writer), 1989 (Box 31)
    - Murphy, Michael, 1991 (Box 31)
    - Nabokov, Ivan (publisher), 2000-2002 (Box 32)
    - Nagano, Paul T. (painter), 1976-2003 (Box 32)
    - National Endowment of the Arts, 1976 (Box 32)
    - Naylor, Gloria (writer), 1989 (Box 32)
    - New Yorker Magazine, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Niece, Gerry, 1981 (Box 40)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art (NCMA), 1996-1998 (Box 32)
    - Nunez, Sigrid (writer), 1982 (Box 32)
    - Nydick, Leslie, 1995 Jan 26 (Box 40)
    - Oxenhorn, Harvey (academic, author), 1982-1989 (Box 32)
    - Patchett, Ann (writer), 1991-1996; undated (Box 32)
    - Paley, Grace (writer), 1980-1993; undated (Box 32)
    - Pantheon Books, undated (Box 32)
    - Paschal, Huston (editor), undated (Box 32)
    - Patterson, Ippy (artist), 2001 (Box 32)
      aka Barbara Tarleton Astlett
    - Petrocchi, Russell, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Pilcer, Sonia (writer), 1979 (Box 32)
    - Pollan, Michael (writer), 1989-1996 (Box 32)
    - Pope, L.B., 1999 (Box 42)
    - Preservation Magazine, undated (Box 32)
    - Price, David (politician), 1994 (Box 32)
    - Price, Reynolds (author, professor), 1981-1993 (Box 32)
    - Price, William, 2011 (Box 32)
    - Random House Audio, 1991-2000 (Box 32)
    - Reed, John Shelton (writer), 1996 (Box 32)
      Random House published audio versions of Oldest Living Confederate Widow and White People.
    - Reichlein, Georg, 1989-1996; undated (Box 32)
    - Riner, Ed (Forbes magazine editor), 1968 (Box 32)
    - Richardson, Amy, 1990-1991; undated (Box 32)
    - Ring, Frances, 2004 (Box 32)
      Frances Ring was F. Scott Fitzgerald's secretary from 1939-1940.
    - Roberts, Dorothy E. "Dot" (Duke administrative assistant), 1989 (Box 32)
    - Rogers, Betsy, 1966-1998 (Box 32)
    - Rorem, Ned (composer), 1990 (Box 32)
    - Rosenthal, John (photographer), 2017-2018 (Box 32)
    - Royster, Frances (Bonnie), 1982-1991; undated (Box 32)
    - Sanford, Mary, 1994; 1996 (Box 32)
    - Sapp, B. Daniel, 1990; undated (Box 32)
    - Saylor, Bruce (composer), 1981-2013; undated (Box 33)
    - Schneebaum, Tobias (artist), 1982-1997; undated (Box 33)
    - Schnur, Steven (writer), 1989 (Box 33)
    - Scowcroft, Richard (writer), 1990 (Box 33)
    - Segal, Lore (writer), 1976 (Box 33)
    - Simon, Andrea (filmmaker), 1982-1996; undated (Box 33)
    - Simon and Schuster, 1995 (Box 33)
    - Simon, Peter, 1976 (Box 33)
      Includes information on documentary about dancer and choreographer, Bessie Schonberg.
    - Simpson, Eileen (writer), 1976-1989 (Box 33)
    - Simpson, Mona (writer, editor), 1989-1993; undated (Box 33)
    - Sklarew, Myra (biologist, poet), 1989; undated (Box 33)
    - Slouka, Mark (writer), 2002; undated (Box 33)
    - Smith, Elise, 2003 (Box 33)
    - Smith, Leverett Terry (professor), 1977-2007; undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Smith, Terry, 1998 (Box 40)
    - Speight, Sarah Blakeslee (painter), 1993 (Box 33)
    - Spencer, Elizabeth (writer), 1993-1996; undated (Box 33)
    - Spiro, Ellen (filmmaker), 1990-1996; undated (Box 33)
    - Steele, Max (writer), 1996 (Box 33)
    - Stewart, Ann (artist), 1982-1996; undated (Box 33)
    - Stewart, Joyce, 1989-1992; undated (Box 33)
    - Stewart, Susan (poet), 1990 (Box 33)
    - Stockwell, Anne (editorf), 1997 (Box 33)
    - Sultan, Altoon (artist, writer), 1989 (Box 33)
    - Sundell, Mike (president, Yaddo), 1998; undated (Box 33)
    - Szabo Rostock, Susanne (filmmaker), undated (Box 33)
    - Tartt, Donna (writer), 1995 (Box 33)
    - Taylor, Paul (dancer, choreographer), 1981-2013; 16 folders (Box 34)
      Includes correspondence between Gurganus and long time friend, dancer and choreographer Paul Taylor. Along with postcards and letters, Taylor often sent DVDs and programs for the Paul Taylor Dance Company, and personal items including condoms, loose sand and feathers.
    - Taylor, Paul (dancer, choreographer), 2008-2015; undated; 21 items (Box 72, Dvd RL11748-DVD-0001 - RL11748-DVD-0021)
      Series contains fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
      DVD titles include: Gossamer Gallants; Death and the Damsel; Sullivaniana; To Make Crops Grow; Beloved Renegade; Sea Lark; Creative Domain; American Dreamer; Dilly Dilly; House of Joy; Marathon Cadenzas; Three Dubious Memories; Perpetual Dawn; and, The Man Behind the Dance.
    - Taylor, Paul (dancer, choreographer), 2014-2016; undated; 4 folders (Box 35)
    - Theroux, Alexander (writer), 1989 (Box 35)
    - Thompson, Jean (writer), 1989 (Box 35)
    - Thorp, Daisy (art professor), 1967-1988; 8 folders (Box 35)
      Includes correspondence from Gurganus to Thorp.
    - Thorp, Daisy (art professor), 1989-1993; 1995; 6 folders (Box 36)
    - Thorp, Daisy (art professor), 1996-1998; undated; 7 folders (Box 37)
    - Thorp, Daisy (art professor), undated; 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Thorp, Daisy (art professor), 1976-2008; undated (Box 41)
    - Tillich, Hannah (painter), undated (Box 38)
    - Troxler, Allan (artist), 1995; undated (Box 38)
    - Truitt, Anne (sculptor), 1989-1994 (Box 38)
    - Unnamed, undated (Box 42)
    - USA Today, 1989 (Box 38)
    - Urban, Amanda "Binky" (literary agent), 2000; undated (Box 38)
    - Vance, Jane Gentry (poet), 1993 (Box 38)
    - Vaterlaus, Anne Elizabeth (landscape architect), 1989-1990; undated (Box 38)
    - Vecchi, Floriano (artist), 1992 (Box 38)
    - Vereano, David (artist), 1983 (Box 38)
    - Walker, Alice (writer), 1975 (Box 38)
    - Warren, Rebecca Drane, 2013 (Box 38)
    - Watson, Ben, 1986; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Wechsler, Jane (educator, married to Bruce Gurganus), 1989-1998; undated (Box 39)
    - Wechsler, Jane, undated (Box 42)
    - Wheeler, Lawrence, 1996-1998 (Box 39)
    - White, Edmund (writer), 1980-1997; undated (Box 39)
    - Wiley, Dick (writer), 1989 (Box 39)
    - Willett, Richard (writer), 1999; undated (Box 39)
    - Williams, Donald, 1991-1997 (Box 39)
    - Williams, Jonathan (poet), 1992-1997 (Box 39)
    - Wilson, Helen (artist), 1988-1998; undated (Box 39)
    - Wolff, Tobias (writer), 1989-2013 (Box 39)
    - Wolitzer, Hilma (writer), 1976-2000 (Box 39)
    - Woodman, Tim (sculptor), 1990-1996; undated (Box 39)
    - Yaddo, 1982-2005 (Box 39)
      Yaddo is a writer's community in Sarasota Springs, New York, frequented by Gurganus.
- Personal Papers, 1917-2018; undated
  This Series includes family correspondence; early drawings; books; photographs; and audiovisual materials.
  - Family Correspondence, 1917-1996; undated
    Correspondence includes World War II letters between Allan's parents, Ethel and Marvin Gurganus; letters from Allan to his parents written while in college; in the Navy; and later living in New York city and is arranged chronologically. Also included is correspondence between other Gurganus family members.
    - Correspondence, 1962; 1965-1975; 9 folders (Box 43)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1983; 1986; 1988-1996; undated; 7 folders (Box 44)
    - Other family correspondence, 1917; 1968; undated (Box 44)
    - Gurganus, Bruce, 1968-1996; undated (Box 45)
    - Gurganus, Bruce, 1990; undated; 2 folders (Box 42)
      Includes newspaper article on a gay film festival, and oversized correspondence.
    - Gurganus, Ethel, 1969-1995; undated; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Gurganus, Ethel, 1971 (Box 42)
      Handmade birthday card by Gurganus, and oversized correspondence.
    - Gurganus, Ethel and Marvin, 1989; 1994; undated (Box 45)
    - Gurganus, Marvin and Ethel, 1965-1992; 4 folders (Box 40)
      Includes a newspaper article about AIDS, and oversized correspondence.
    - Gurganus, Marvin and Ethel, 1977; 1981; 2 folders (Box 42)
      Correspondence includes World War II letters between Gurganus's parents, Ethel and Marvin Gurganus; letters from Gurganus to his parents written while in college; in the Navy; and later living in New York City and is arranged chronologically. Also included is correspondence between other Gurganus family members.
    - Gurganus, Gary, 1968; 1978; undated (Box 45)
    - Gurganus, Marvin, 1965-1995; undated (Box 45)
    - Gurganus, William, 1981-1995 (Box 45)
  - Family Papers, 1942-2003; undated
    This subseries includes original Gurganus family documents; newspaper clippings; and records, and is arranged by type of item.
    - Hospital baby records, 1942 (Box 46)
    - US Air Force diploma, 1943 (Box 46)
    - Marvin and Ethel correspondence, 1940-1945; 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus wedding gift record, 1946 (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus writing, 1990-1995; undated; 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus writing, 1989 (Box 67)
      Includes No Yolk.
    - Ethel Gurganus article, undated (Box 46)
    - Gurganus travel papers, 1970-1981; undated; 4 folders (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus letter, undated (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus's teaching certificate, 1946 (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus's classroom list, undated (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus USO club pamphlet, undated (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus eulogy, 1996 (Box 46)
    - Memorial Service of Marvin Gurganus, 1995 Dec 7 (Box 72, Audio-cassette RL11748-CS-0006)
    - Aunt Dell's 90th birthday, 2003 Apr (Box 46)
    - Ethel Gurganus Mother's Day card, undated (Box 46)
    - H. Gurganus article, 1978 (Box 46)